Guide to the John Galsworthy Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Galsworthy collection
1904-1931
GEN MSS 278
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.4
(1 box)
Contains letters from Galsworthy to various people, including John Drinkwater, Henry Albert Phillips, and Geza Silberer; and writings of Galsworthy, including "The Silver Box" and "Strife."
Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box-and-folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to John Galsworthy, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection.
Silver box: a comedy in three acts; Strife: a drama in three acts; Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937; Galsworthy, Ada, -1956; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933; Phillips, Henry Albert, 1880-1951; Sil-Vara, 1876-1938
- Letters from John Galsworthy, 1914 Jan 24; Series I
  - Postcard to George and Christina Baker, Winter Palace, Luxor, Egypt, 1914 Jan 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Signed "John and Ada Galsworthy."
    Gift, 1954.
  - ALS to Professor Barker, London, 1923 Sep 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    With ALS to [Cecil] Driver, London,
    Mar 11.
    Gift, 1959.
  - ANS to Frances Bolton, Hampstead, London, 1929 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    With envelope.
    Gift, 1949.
  - ALS (facsimile) to John Cournos, Sussex, 1928 Oct 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gift, 1952.
  - 76 ALS (1 fragment) and 9 letters to John Drinkwater, 1911-31, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    In Ada Galsworthy's hand but signed
    by John Galsworthy.
    Purchase, 1953.
  - ALS to Frank P. Harris, London, 1929 Sep 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ALS to Adam de Hegedüs, Majorca, 1929 Dec 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    With envelope. Accompanied by the
    typescript of an interview between
    Galsworthy and de Hegedüs, corrected
    by Galsworthy and the final typescript
    entitled: "An Hour with Mr. John
    Galsworthy
    Purchase, 1954.
  - ALS to Mrs. Hills, Grand Hotel, Levanto, près Spezia, Italy, 1905 Jan 31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Purchase, 1959.
  - ALS to Dr. Leon Kellner, London, 1913 Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    About Gerhart Hauptmann. With
    manuscript copy of the letter.
  - 18 ALS to Rudolf Kommer, 1912-25 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    Some with envelopes.
    Purchase, 1958.
  - 20 ALS and 1 APcS to J. Kuylman, 1913-27, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    List of plays enclosed with ALS dated
    Apr 19.
    Purchase, 1956.
  - ALS to G. M., England, 1918 Nov 11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Concerning conscientious objectors.
  - ALS to Helen MacAfee, Hampstead, London, N.W. 3, 1930 Oct 29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Gift, 1944.
  - ALS to Mrs. Massingham, London, 1925 Oct 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - LS, to Cecil Palmer, Manaton, Devon, 1918 Oct 16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    In the hand of Ada Galsworthy.
    Purchase, 1975.
  - ALS to Bernard Partridge, London, 1918 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ALS to Miss Patching, London, 1929 Jul 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2 ANS and 3 NS to Henry Albert Phillips, 1925-27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Accompanied by a typed copy of
    Henry Albert Phillips' account of an
    interview with John Galsworthy,
    heavily corrected by the latter [?]
    Also accompanied by an extra
    envelope (addressed to Henry Albert
    Phillips and postmarked 1925 Dec 7)
    and a mimeographed card reading "Mr
    and Mrs John Galsworthy are away for
    the whole winter."
    Gift, 1951.
  - ALS to James B. Pinker, London, 1906 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 3 ALS to Miss Sanders, 1928-29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Concerning short stories by Karel Capek. Accompanied by signed typescript of Galsworthy's foreword for Capek's Money and Other Stories. Gift, 1952.
  - ALS to Geza Silberer, 1914 Feb 17 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ALS to Charles Wilson, London, 1926 Jun 21 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    With envelope. Accompanied by
    photograph of Galsworthy's home,
    Grove Lodge, inscribed on verso by
    him.
    Gift, 1969.
  - ALS to "My dear Jack," 16A Aubrey Walk, Campden Hill, W., 1904 Nov 21 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    With envelope inscribed: "J. W. H."
  - ALS to unidentified recipient, Sussex, 1926 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Accompanied by cancelled check,
    endorsed by Galsworthy.
  - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1929 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Gift, 1964.
- Other, 1915 Sep 4; Series II
  - Biographical form completed for (Harrow) Old Public School Boys Who's Who and Roll of Honour, Sussex, 1915 Sep 4 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Living American Writers: Some Whose Books Have Given Me Pleasure", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Autograph manuscript in pencil,
    listing 8 American authors.
    Accompanied by an ALS from Mrs. Ada
    Galsworthy to an unidentified
    recipient authenticating the above
    manuscript, Hampstead, N.W.S., 1934
    Dec 17.
    Purchase, 1944.
  - "The Prayer", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Typescript poem. Removed from: Candelabra by John Galsworthy (New York, 1933). Gift, 1961.
  - "The Silver Box," New York, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
    A play in typescript. An acting copy.
    In 3 notebooks.
    Gift, 1958.
  - "Strife: A Drama in Three Acts", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Typed copy, signed, in volume.